servicepower.com 2011-06-05

# SERVICEPower - Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

US | UK

**UK Privacy Policy**

**SERVICEPOWER BUSINESS SOLUTIONS LIMITED** ("We" “us” “our”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the **Act)** , the data controller is SERVICEPower Business Solutions Limited of Petersgate House, St Petersgate, Stockport, Cheshire, SK1 1HE

Our nominated representative for the purpose of the Act is **Kathryne Jobling**

**Information we may collect from you**

We may collect and process the following data about you, both personal information that you knowingly choose to disclose and information collected by us as you interact on our site. This includes the following: 

  * Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our site, subscribing to our services, posting material, downloading material or requesting further services. **** We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our site.
  * If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.
  * We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.
  * Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of our obligations to you.
  * Details of your visits to our site including, and the resources that you access, including but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and any other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

**IP addresses and cookies**

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:

  * To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.
  * To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests.
  * To speed up your searches.
  * To recognise you when you return to our site. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

**Where we store your personal data**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ("EEA"). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our associated companies or suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**Uses made of the information**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. 
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our services, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our services.

We may also use your data to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we may contact you about these by post or telephone.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means **** (email or SMS) with information about goods or services similar to those which were the subject of a previous contract.

If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will only contact you by electronic means if you have consented to this.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the order form).

**Disclosure of your information**

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In connection with the negotiation or fulfilment of contracts involving those third parties, whether as customers or suppliers
  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If SERVICEPower Business Solutions Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use **** or other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of any company in the SERVICEPower group, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**Your rights**

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting Kathryne Jobling at SERVICEPower Business Solutions Ltd, Petersgate House, St Petersgate, Stockport, Cheshire, England SK1 1HE or at [ k.jobling@servicepower.com](mailto:k.jobling@servicepower.com).

You also have the right to see all personal data which we hold about you and to ask us to delete or correct any information which is inaccurate.

**Access to information**

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act. Any access request may be subject to a fee of ?10 to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

**Contact**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [ k.jobling@servicepower.com](mailto:k.jobling@servicepower.com).

**US Privacy Policy**

**SERVICEPOWER INC** ("We" “us” “our”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

We participate in the Safe Harbor program and adhere to the Safe Harbor Principles developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce and the European Union. For more information about the Safe Harbor program, please visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s [ http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/](http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/).  This policy together with our terms of use and any other documents referred to on it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

The data controller is SERVICEPower Inc of 1503 South Coast Drive, Suite 320, Costa Mesa, CA92626

Our nominated representative for the purpose of the Safe Harbor Principles is `E.U. Data Protection Authorities. `

**Information we may collect from you**

We may collect and process the following data about you, both personal information that you knowingly choose to disclose and information collected by us as you interact on our site. This includes the following: 

Information that you provide by filling in forms on our site. This includes information provided at the time of registering to use our site, subscribing to our services, posting material, downloading material or requesting further services. **** We may also ask you for information when you report a problem with our site.

If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

We may also ask you to complete surveys that we use for research purposes, although you do not have to respond to them.

Details of transactions you carry out through our site and of the fulfilment of our obligations to you.

Details of your visits to our site including, and the resources that you access, including but not limited to, traffic data, location data, weblogs and any other communication data, whether this is required for our own billing purposes or otherwise and the resources that you access.

**IP addresses and cookies**

We may collect information about your computer, including where available your IP address, operating system and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. This is statistical data about our users' browsing actions and patterns, and does not identify any individual.

For the same reason, we may obtain information about your general internet usage by using a cookie file which is stored on the hard drive of your computer. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive. They help us to improve our site and to deliver a better and more personalised service. They enable us:

  * To estimate our audience size and usage pattern.
  * To store information about your preferences, and so allow us to customise our site according to your individual interests.
  * To speed up your searches.
  * To recognise you when you return to our site. 

You may refuse to accept cookies by activating the setting on your browser which allows you to refuse the setting of cookies. However, if you select this setting you may be unable to access certain parts of our site. Unless you have adjusted your browser setting so that it will refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies when you log on to our site.

**TRANSMISSION OF PERSONAL DATA**

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

**Uses made of the information**

We use information held about you in the following ways:

  * To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer. 
  * To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes. 
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our services, when you choose to do so.
  * To notify you about changes to our services.

We may also use your data to provide you with information about goods and services which may be of interest to you and we may contact you about these by post or telephone.

If you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means **** (email or SMS) with information about goods or services similar to those which were the subject of a previous contract.

If you are a new customer, and where we permit selected third parties to use your data, we (or they) will only contact you by electronic means if you have consented to this.

If you do not want us to use your data in this way, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the order form).

**Disclosure of your information**

We may disclose your personal information to any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In connection with the negotiation or fulfilment of contracts involving those third parties, whether as customers or suppliers
  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If SERVICEPower Inc or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use **** or other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of any company in the SERVICEPower group, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

**Your rights**

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting Mark Homer at 1503 South Coast Drive, Suite 320, Costa Mesa, CA 92626 or at [ privacy@servicepower.com](mailto:privacy@servicepower.com).

You also have the right to see all personal data which we hold about you and to ask us to delete or correct any information which is inaccurate.

**Access to information**

You have the right to access information held about you. For further information about your right of access, please contact us at the above address. Any access request may be subject to a fee to meet our costs in providing you with details of the information we hold about you.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.

**Contact**

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [ k.jobling@servicepower.com](mailto:k.jobling@servicepower.com).

**DISPUTE RESOLUTION AND ENFORCEMENT**

In the event of any dispute between us, we agree to cooperate and comply with any ruling or instructions made by the UK Information Commission.  Details of how to contact the Information Commission are available at [ www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/).
